(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
履いて捨てるような現実は
A reality that can be discarded
一刀両断、叩き斬る！
I'll cut it down with one stroke!
終わりなき輪廻に迷いし子らよ。
Oh, children lost in endless samsara.
漆黒の翼で誘おう。
I shall invite you with pitch-black wings.
我らエデンの星を統べる者、
We are the rulers of the planet Eden,
秘密結社...
The secret society...
holoXでござる！
is holoX!
皆の者、かかれ！
Everyone, attack!
Yes My Dark!
イエーーーイ！！
YAAAY!!
どうだ貴様ら！最高にカッコよかっただろう！
How was it, you scoundrels? We were super cool, right?!
めちゃくちゃよかったよね！
That was incredibly good, wasn't it?!
合図決まった！
The cue was perfect!
最高！
Awesome!
初めて決まった！
We nailed it for the first time!
ちゃんと練習した甲斐があったね。
It was really worth practicing properly.
甲斐があったぞ！
It was definitely worth it!
甲斐があった～！
It was worth it~!
そしてここが、我らのアジトだ！
And here is our hideout!
イエーーーイ！ジャジャーン！
YAAAY! Ta-da!
え、待って。秘密結社なのにアジトを公開していいのかい？
Wait, is it okay to reveal our hideout even though we're a secret society?
いいの！
It's fine!
いいの！窓ないからね！
It's fine! Because there are no windows!
そうだよ。あのエロい奴しかないから。
Exactly. We only have that sexy thing.
エロいピンクの奴しかないから！
We only have that sexy pink thing!
あの明かりちょっとエロい...
That light is a bit sexy...
確かに、それはある。
That's true, actually.
吾輩はね、結構住み心地良くて気に入ってるよ。
As for me, it's quite comfortable to live in and I like it.
じゃ、色々紹介したいところはあるんだけれども、
Well, there are many things we want to introduce,
今日の配信のハッシュタグ、皆に教えましょう！
but let's tell everyone the hashtag for today's stream!
いろは側にあるやつね。カモン！
The one over by Iroha. Come on!
#SSholoX
ハッシュタグ #SSholoX で呟いてくださったら嬉しいです！
We'd be happy if you tweet with the hashtag #SSholoX!
たくさん呟いてね～！
Tweet a lot, okay~!
呟いてね～！
Please tweet!
お願いします！
Please do!
頼んだ。
I'm counting on you.
はい。じゃあ、紹介していく？
Alright. Shall we start the tour?
紹介したーい！
I want to do the intro!
紹介したいよね！
We definitely want to!
ぐるぐるぐるぐる...どこから行こうかな？
Spinning around... where should we start?
じゃあ、吾輩のソファ！吾輩のソファ！
Then, my sofa! My sofa!
あ、吾輩のソファ。
Ah, her sofa.
めっちゃいい椅子座ってる！
She's sitting in a really nice chair!
見て見て！
Look, look!
吾輩、椅子も持ってるし、ソファも持ってるし、
I have a chair, and a sofa,
で、カラスもいるんだよ。
and there's a crow too.
カラスもいるんだ。
There's a crow too.
ダーツで遊んでんの。
I play with darts.
あ、そうだ！できんの？ダーツ。
Oh, right! Can you actually play darts?
できんの？
Can you?
でも遊んでるとこ見たことない。
But I've never seen you playing.
うるさい黙れ！いいの！イマジナリーダーツ！
Shut up! It's fine! Imaginary darts!
次々！博士のを見よう！
Next, next! Let's see the Doctor's!
あ、こよりのところは、ここです！
Ah, Koyori's place is right here!
ええ、すごい！
Whoa, amazing!
いいじゃん、可愛い！
It's nice and cute!
地図も飾ってあるし、ゲーミングチェア！
There's a map on the wall, and a gaming chair!
いつもね、頭抱えながら頑張ってるよ、ここで。
I'm always working hard here, holding my head.
たまにここが爆発するけど、みんな気にしないで。優しい。
Sometimes this place explodes, but everyone is kind enough not to mind.
可愛いー！
So cute!
端っこにしたからね。
I put it in the corner.
まあ、我が輩被ってるけど。
Well, it's overlapping with me though.
まあ、ラプラスならいっか。
Well, if it's Laplus, it's fine.
どういう扱いだよ！ふざけんな！
What's with that treatment?! Don't mess with me!
じゃあ次行くか。
Well, shall we go to the next one?
うん！
Yeah!
はーい！
Okay!
ここはドーン！
And here is... Ta-da!
幹部だ！
It's the Executive's area!
そう、私のね、キッチン。愛用してるキッチンですね。
Yes, it's my kitchen. The kitchen I use regularly.
まあ幹部室はね、また2階とかにあるんだけれども。
Well, the executive room is on the second floor, but...
ここでね、みんなの、まあご飯だったりとか、ラプラスに向けてね、ハンバーグなど作っています。
Here, I make rice for everyone, and things like Hamburg steak for Laplus.
ハンバーグ！
Hamburg steak!
ガムもある、ガムもね。
I also have gum, you see.
ハンバーグ食べようね。
Let's eat Hamburg steak.
生姜焼きも！
And ginger pork too!
お上手！
You're so good!
いっぱいいっぱい。そして...
So many things. And...
ここに行くと...
If you go here...
見て見て！沙花叉のお掃除道具が飾られてます！
Look, look! Sakamata's cleaning tools are on display!
できんの？
Can you actually do it?
掃除するもの違くない？
Aren't the things you clean different?
掃除してるとこ見たことないんだけど。
I've never seen you clean anything before.
ちゃんと掃除屋さんだからね、お掃除なんですけど。
I'm a proper cleaner, so of course I clean.
あとあの、拘束テープ貼ってあるので、皆さん覗かないでください。上のね、段ボールとか見ないでね。
Also, there's caution tape, so please don't peek. Don't look at the cardboard boxes on top!
でも掃除してるとこ見たことないよ。
But we've never seen you clean.
ダメダメ、見たことないよ。
No, no, I've never seen it either.
次、侍でござる。
Next is the samurai.
まあ風真は荷物少ないでござるからな。
Well, Kazama has very little luggage.
いや本当に！
Seriously!
本当にね！
Really, right!
片付いてるわ。
It's so tidy.
ナスじゃ！
It's an eggplant!
ナス！
Eggplant!
ナス、ごはん、ごはん。
Eggplant, food, food.
ナスはごはんでござる。
Eggplant is food.
え、これ今日食べるやつだよね？今日料理するやつ。
Wait, this is the one you're eating today, right? The one for cooking today.
冷蔵庫にしまっとけばいいじゃん。
You should just put it in the fridge.
まあね、あの、すぐ取り出せるように生であそこに置いてあるでござる。
Well, it's placed there raw so I can take it out and eat it immediately.
やめてー！
Stop it!
生？！
Raw?!
あとぽこべぇ！
And Pokobe!
ぽこべぇー！
Pokobe!
招き猫みたいになってる。
It looks like a maneki-neko.
福が訪れるからね。置いてあります。
It's there because it brings good luck.
あと帯の予備とかも置いてあるでござる。
Also, I have a spare obi placed there.
可愛い！
Cute!
So cute!
これこれ、これ！
This, this, this one!
幹部の鞭と一緒に置いてあるんだよね。
It's placed together with the Executive's whip.
あー、えっち！
Oh, that's erotic!
えっちだなぁ。
How sexy.
こんな感じになってます、皆さんどうですか？
It's like this, everyone. How is it?
なんかいつもはこんな感じだけど...あ、いつもじゃねえわ、今日はこんな感じだけど。
It's usually like this... no, it's like this today, but...
いつもはもっと違うんだよ。
It's usually much different.
この辺にいろいろ置いてあるのを今日撤去したんだよ。
I moved various things that are usually around here for today.
片付けたでござる。
We tidied up.
今日のためにね。
For today's sake.
いつものやつ見て、せーの！
Take a look at how it usually is. Ready...!
どうぞ！
Ta-da!
わあー！
Whoa!
いつもこのソファで寝てる。
I'm always sleeping on this sofa.
くつろいでるね。
You're really relaxing.
なんか真ん中片付けておけばよかったね。
Maybe we should have tidied up the middle.
コーラだ、コーラ！
Coke! There's a Coke!
うるさい、うるさい！いいんだよ！
Shut up, shut up! It's fine!
なんか出しっぱなしのやつに言われたくないんだよ。
I don't want to hear that from someone who leaves things out.
いいだろ別に！
Who cares! It's fine!
まあ誰が食べてるかすぐわかるな。
Well, you can tell immediately who's eating what.
うるさいなぁ。あ、そうだ、今日のハッシュタグ！
You're so annoying. Oh, right, today's hashtag!
#SSholoX！
#SSholoX!
うるさい！というわけで。
Shut up! Anyway...
えっと、我々がね、この6月でどんどん3Dお披露目していってだな。
So, we've all been having our 3D debuts this June.
世界征服に向けて一歩前進したってことなんですけども。
And we've taken a step forward toward world conquest.
いっぽ、いっぽ！侍、成果どうだった？
One step, one step! Samurai, how was the result?
お、凄楽しかった！
Oh, it was really fun!
そういうことじゃないだろう！
That's not what I meant!
喜んでもらえて。
People were happy.
我が輩に報告しろっつーの！
I said, report to me!
見てた、見てたけど、やっぱ本人の口から聞かないと。
We saw it, we did, but we need to hear it from you.
じゃあ侍から、はい！
Alright then, samurai! Go!
いろはから。行きます！
From Iroha. Here I go!
お！映像がある！
Oh! There's a video!
ファイル1、おー！
File 001, oh!
これなんか公式番組で見たやつ！
I saw this on an official program!
懐かしい！かっこいい！
So nostalgic! And cool!
いっちょーたい！ヘイヘイ！
One-two, showtime! Hey, hey!
ヘイヘイ！いろは！
Hey, hey! Iroha!
あ、出た、出た！大きい！
Oh, there he is! He's big!
今からぽこべぇ、ぽこべぇだよこれ！
Here comes Pokobe, it's Pokobe!
ぽこべぇ3Dお披露目！
It's Pokobe's 3D debut!
風真いろはでござるー！
It's Kazama Iroha!
これ、これ、これが黒井なんじゃないかって言われてたやつ。
This is the one people were saying was Kuroi.
くらえー！
Take this!
かっこいいー！殺陣！
So cool! Action scene!
今のやつ、黒井だよな？
The one just now was Kuroi, right?
嘘だー！誰と戦ったの？
Lies! Who were you fighting?
誠に対戦ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much for the match!
おいおい、おいおい！
Hey, hey!
待って、待って！
Wait, wait!
まあでもね、3D配信でも終始動きっぱなしで風真らしさが見せられたんじゃないかなって。
But I think I was able to show Kazama's style in the 3D stream, moving around the whole time.
いや、めちゃくちゃかっこよかったよ！
Yeah, it was really cool!
体幹の強さね、見せられたんじゃないかなと思っております。
I think I was able to show the strength of my core.
かっこよかった、美しかったよ！
It was cool and beautiful!
剣舞もめっちゃ綺麗だったし。
The sword dance was also very pretty.
あとサラランっていうやつもさ！
And the 'Sararan' part too!
サラランスね、サラランス。
Sararansu, right? Sararansu.
前見えなかったけど、すごいいかった！
I couldn't see well from the front, but it was great!
ありがとうございます。まだ見てない方はぜひ見てください！
Thank you! If you haven't seen it yet, please do!
ぜひぜひ！
Please do!
じゃあなんかさっきお披露目した新人どうだった？
Well, how about the rookie who just debuted earlier?
ねえ、新人じゃないの！あれは沙花叉なの！
Hey, I'm not a rookie! That's Sakamata!
もう、ちゃんとした沙花叉の見てください、どうぞ！
Please watch the proper Sakamata one. Here!
大丈夫か？公式でできんのか？
Is this okay? Can we show this officially?
ホロライブ、心配でござる。
Hololive is worried about this.
ああ、これは… これは違うよね
Ah, this... this isn't right, is it?
ずっと沙花叉と戯れてるじゃん
You're just playing with Sakamata all the time.
やばいやばいやばい
Oh no, oh no, oh no!
よかったね、美しい
That was good, so pretty.
うん、本当によかったよね
Yeah, it was really good.
沙花叉のなんかギャップっていうのが、よかったよね
Sakamata's, like, gap was really good, wasn't it?
ライブパートはめっちゃよかった
The live part was awesome.
でもね、沙花叉さんと戯れてる姿もね、よかったでござる
But seeing you play with Sakamata-san was also good.
よかったよね！
It was good, wasn't it!
水淀んでる感じがあれよね、すごくよかった
That murky water feeling was really good.
反復横跳びが… よかった
The side-to-side jumps were... good.
きもいきもい！ありえなーい！ありえなーい！
Gross, gross! No way! No way!
次行くか
Shall we move to the next one?
じゃあ次は博士のやつ見ようかな
Let's watch the Doctor's next.
見てください！
Please watch!
これ可愛い。絶対可愛かったんだよね
This is cute. That was definitely cute, wasn't it?
健全す… 健全すぎよ
Whole... too wholesome.
嘘！嘘つけ！
Liar! You're lying!
めちゃくちゃよかったよね。めっちゃ感動したよ
That was amazing. I was really moved.
今回はね、ダンスめちゃくちゃ頑張ったから
She worked really hard on the dance this time.
すごかった！
It was amazing!
ずっとずっと尻尾振ってたんだよね
My tail was wagging the whole time.
めちゃくちゃ可愛いんだ。イマジナリー尻尾が振ってるかのような
It's so cute. Like an imaginary tail was wagging.
初めてのオリジナル曲だからでも嬉しい、仲間に戻ってもらえて
It's my first original song, so I'm happy to have everyone back together.
見てください！
Please watch it!
じゃあ次最後に幹部見ようか
Next, let's watch the Officer last.
見ましょう
Let's watch.
でももう記憶に新しいんじゃないかな
But it's probably still fresh in your memory, right?
最近だね
It was recent.
じたばたしないの！
Don't struggle!
じたばたする悪い子はお仕置きがあるよ
Bad kids who struggle will get a punishment.
お仕置きください！
Please punish me!
もみもみしないの
Don't squeeze!
イラストもめっちゃ嬉しかった
I was so happy about the illustration too.
やっぱりね、あの憧れのステージでみんなで立ちたいなっていう夢があって
After all, I had a dream of standing on that stage I've long admired with everyone.
ちょっとみんなを出したいなと思ってイラストをちょっとね
I wanted to include everyone, so I had that illustration made.
やばいそれは
That's crazy.
やっぱり私もね、夢を見たいから、みんなで夢を見たいなっていうことで、ああいう演出にさせていただきました
After all, I want to dream too, so I wanted to dream with everyone, which is why I made that kind of production.
めちゃくちゃよかった
It was so good.
沙花叉のお手紙もよかったよ
Chloe's letter was good too.
やばいから！みんなが泣いちゃう
It's dangerous! Everyone will cry.
ぜひアーカイブで見てください
Please watch the archive.
そして何か先ほど最後って言ってたけどね
And although I said "the last" just now...
うちの総帥も素晴らしい3Dお披露目をしているので
Our Leader also had a wonderful 3D debut.
見ようや
Let's watch it.
ラプラスのVTRどうぞ
Here is La+ Darknesss' VTR.
なんで？なんで笑うの？
Why? Why are you laughing?
京都！ラプラスとのデートじゃん
Kyoto! It's a date with Laplus.
これ一番センシティブじゃない？
Isn't this the most sensitive part?
何も見えてないから
You can't see anything.
めちゃくちゃよかったよね
It was amazing.
やっぱりね、VLOG撮れたのがよかった
After all, I'm glad I could film the VLOG.
今までにない3Dお披露目だったよね
It was a 3D debut like never before.
ずっと前からありたいって言ってたことができたから
I was able to do what I'd been saying I wanted to do for a long time.
暇だったら見てよ
Watch it if you're free.
見てください！
Please watch it!
ねぇ。
Hey.
広いアジト、うれしいね。
It's great having a spacious lair, isn't it?
ねぇ。
Yeah.
何なの？
What is it?
照れちゃって、もう。
You're so shy.
五人の見ていただけに。
Just by seeing the five of us...
皆さん、3Dお披露目おめでとう。
Everyone, congratulations on your 3D reveal.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ところで、holoXの目的、忘れてないですか？
By the way, have you forgotten holoX's goal?
え？
Eh?
世界征服だろーよ！
It's world conquest!
成長を見るために、世界征服、そして秘密結社に必要な能力をチェックします。
To see your growth, we'll check the skills needed for world conquest and a secret society.
秘密結社に必要な能力とは、何でしょうね？
What are the skills necessary for a secret society?
急にクイズ始まったんだけど！
A quiz suddenly started?!
今回は能力をチェックする企画を用意しています。
We have prepared a project to check your abilities this time.
何も答え出てないまま、勝手に進められるんだけど。
It's just moving forward without any answers.
幹部？
Exec?
お前、グルか？
Are you in on this?
違う、違う、違う！
No, no, no!
メモ用紙を渡すので、いい感じにどうぞ。
I'll hand out some memo pads, so please do your best.
適当だなー。
So vague.
メモ用紙？
Memo pads?
おー、来た来た。
Oh, here they come.
雑だなー、雑！
So rough! So rough!
はい、ちょっとめちゃくちゃ無茶振りされたんですけどね。
Yes, I was given quite an unreasonable request.
メモ、ちょっと読んでいきましょう。
Let's read the memo.
お願いします。
Please do.
えっーと、まず最初の能力は...
Um, first of all, the first skill is...
「洞察力」。
Insight.
洞察力！
Insight!
洞察力って何ですか？
What is insight?
まあ、何か見極める能力みたいな感じかな？
Well, I guess it's something like the ability to discern things?
オッケー。
Okay.
ということで、チャレンジする企画はこちら！
So, here is the project we'll be challenging!
「holoX Secret Container Boxの中身を、探れ！！」
holoX Secret Container - Guess what's inside the box!!
めっちゃ用意してる！
They've prepared so much!
どんどん、どんどん、何、何、何？
What, what, what's coming next?
召喚される。
It's being summoned.
何や、これ？
What's this?
召喚の儀が行われてる。
A summoning ritual is taking place.
でもこれさ、いつも使ってるやつじゃん。
But wait, this is what we always use.
これ我が家にあるやつ。
This is the one in my house.
みんなで使ってるやつだ。
It's the one we all use.
ラプラスちっちゃ。
Laplus is so small.
うるせーな。
Shut up!
いつもお菓子箱だね。
It's always a snack box.
菓子とか言うな！かっこいいやつだから！
Don't call it a snack box! It's a cool one!
たくさんお菓子を入れてる所なんですけれども、こちらを使って。
It's where we keep lots of snacks, but using this...
私が見本を見せなきゃいけないみたいなので、何をするか分かんないんですけど。
It seems I have to show an example, though I don't know what I'll be doing.
箱の中身を当てる的な感じみたいですね。
It seems like it's about guessing what's inside the box.
なるほどね。
I see.
じゃあ、ふに落ちないけど、私が先にやってみましょう。
Well, I'm not entirely convinced, but let me go first.
見本見せてくれよ。
Show us an example.
目隠しをする？
Do I wear a blindfold?
じゃあ、沙花叉が目隠ししたい！
Then, Sakamata wants to do the blindfolding!
それちょっと大丈夫？
Is that really okay?
変なこと考えてないでござる。
I'm not thinking about anything weird.
じゃあちょっとお願いします。
Then, please go ahead.
お、いいかな？
Oh, is this good?
やめろよ！
Stop it!
間違っちゃった？
Did I make a mistake?
前が分かんないじゃない！
I can't tell which way is front!
あー、おー、オッケーオッケー。
Ah, oh, okay, okay.
お前どこ連れて行くんや。
Where are you taking me?
こっちこっち。
This way, this way.
じゃあ、箱の中身、誰かやってもらってもいいかな？
Then, can someone put something in the box?
代わりにやりますね！入れ込むものは、こちらです！
We'll do it for you! The item going in is this!
おー！
Oh!
確かに分かりやすい。
Certainly easy to tell.
これはさすがに分かるんじゃないか？
Surely she can tell what this is?
大丈夫なやつかな？
Is it something safe?
お前大丈夫だ、怖くない！
You'll be fine, it's not scary!
ちょっと噛み付くかもしれない。
It might bite a little.
噛み付く噛み付く。
It bites, it bites.
変なこと考えてないでござる。
Don't think of anything weird.
結構おとなしい方だと思うけどな。
I think it's pretty well-behaved.
制限時間20秒で行きましょう！
Let's go with a 20-second time limit!
せーの、ドン！
Ready, go!
音はしてないから大丈夫だ。いくわ。
It's not making any sound, so it's fine. Here I go.
噛み付くかもしれん。
It might bite.
おー、どうだ？頑張れ！
Oh, how is it? Do your best!
あ、これ何か分かるぞ。私よく使ってる。
Ah, I know what this is. I use it often.
えっーと、かき回しのやつ。
Um, the stirring thing.
料理に使う、かき回し器！
Used for cooking, a stirring tool!
終了！
Finished!
それじゃあ、答えをお願いします！
Well then, please give us your answer!
あ！答えは...！
Oh! The answer is...!
泡だて器！泡だて器！
A whisk! A whisk!
あ、泡だて器！
Ah, a whisk!
正解です！泡だて器！
Correct! A whisk!
もう、答え出てたから...！
The answer was already out there...!
茹でたから... かき混ぜるやつって言ってた。
I said 'the thing you stir with' because I boiled it.
よかった！
Thank goodness!
今度はちょろ... ちょろいな...
This time it's easy... so easy...
意外になんとかなるでござるな。
It surprisingly works out somehow, doesn't it?
大丈夫だったね。
It was fine, wasn't it?
いつもいる人だからね。
Because she's someone who's always here.
わんこ... 吾輩だったらわかんないかも...
A dog... If it was me, I might not have known...
泡だて器が出てこない...
The word 'whisk' wouldn't come to mind...
動いてなくなさそうだったから大丈夫かなと思って、ガッてやったら大丈夫だったね。
It didn't seem like it was moving, so I thought it would be fine, and when I went for it, it was okay.
20秒めちゃくちゃ短いから。短いね。
20 seconds is extremely short. - It is short.
次ラプラスちゃんやってみる？
Want to try next, La+-chan?
ラプラスやってみましょうか。吾輩こういうの得意だからな。
Shall we have La+ try? - I'm good at this sort of thing.
本当に？じゃあ目隠し付けてあげるよ。
Really? Then I'll put the blindfold on you.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
はい、ラプラスちゃん目隠し付けましょうね〜
Okay, let's put the blindfold on La+-chan~
あーっ！
Ahhh!
どうしたどうした？
What happened, what happened?
ちょっと今耳に息が...！
Your breath was just in my ear...!
何やってんだよ！
What are you doing!
ナイス、こよりちゃん。
Nice one, Koyori-chan.
目隠しって言ったらね、誘導しないと。
When we say blindfold, we have to guide her.
ここだよ、ここだよ。
It's here, it's here.
お、これは... 絵面すごい...
Oh, this... the visual is amazing...
入れるものは... こちらですよ！
The thing we're putting in... is this!
はい、ラプラスの入れ物に入ってるのはこちら！
Yes, what's in La+'s box is this!
これ！わかりますか？
This! Do you know what it is?
やばそう！やばい！
That looks bad! Crazy!
でもなんかラプラスにぴったり。まあね、確かに。
But somehow it's perfect for La+. - Well, true enough.
このまま持って帰っていいよって言いたい感じのね、プレゼントかな？
I feel like telling her she can take it home just like this, like a present?
20秒で当ててもらいましょう！はい、スタート！
Let's have her guess it in 20 seconds! Okay, start!
余裕だよ、これは。
This is a breeze.
どこ？お、え、何だこれは？
Where? Oh, eh, what is this?
大丈夫？ちょっと... 結構小さいからね。
Are you okay? It's quite small.
あ！わかった！わかった！
Ah! I got it! I got it!
わかった？
You got it?
これ、え、言っていいの？いつも使ってるもんね。
This, can you say it? You use it all the time, right?
おしゃぶり！
A pacifier!
おおーっ！速っ！
Whoa! That was fast!
正解 おしゃぶり
Correct: Pacifier
ちょろ！いつも使ってるもんね。
Easy! Since I use it all the time.
いつも使ってるもんねってちょっとヒントだったかもしれない。
Maybe 'you use it all the time' was a bit of a hint.
いつも使ってるタイプのやつ？
Is it the type you always use?
うわ、本当だ！
Whoa, it really is!
なるほどね。
I see.
結構正解してるね。我々の能力あるんじゃん？
We're getting a lot of them right. Maybe we have talent?
じゃあ次はこより行ってみる？
Then, shall we have Koyori go next?
はい、行きます！自信のほどは？
Yes, I'll go! How's your confidence?
でも今まで来てるからね、どんどんと。こよりも頭脳ですから、やっちゃいますよ！
Well, we've been on a roll. Koyori is a brain too, so I'll do it!
やっちゃえやっちゃえ！
Do it, do it!
じゃあ目隠しは風真が付けるでござる。
Then Kazama will put the blindfold on.
お願いします！え、ちょっとエッチなんじゃないですか？
Please! Eh, isn't this a bit lewd?
どこで見ようとしてるんだよ。
Where are you trying to look from?
え、ちょっと！何も見てないから！何も見てないから！
Wait! I'm not looking at anything! I'm not looking at anything!
大丈夫、何もしませんから！
It's okay, I won't do anything!
何もしてないでござるよ！
I'm not doing anything!
じゃあこよりに触ってもらうのはこちら！
Then, what Koyori will touch is this!
お、どこどこ？
Oh, where, where?
ああ、でもこれは当ててほしいかな。
Ah, but I'd like her to guess this one.
博士さすがに... ああ、これね！
As expected of the Doctor... Ah, this!
はい、はい、はい。ありがとうありがとう。
Yes, yes, yes. Thank you, thank you.
じゃあ制限時間20秒で行きましょう！
Then, let's go with a 20-second time limit!
こよりのチャレンジ、スタート！
Koyori's challenge, start!
触らないで一回推理で言うけど、マヨネーズだと思う。
I'll say it based on reasoning without touching first, but I think it's mayonnaise.
ええーっ！？そんなまさか！
Eeeh!? No way!
へ？違う？ケチャップ？崖の... マヨネーズじゃないの？
Eh? No? Ketchup? A cliff... it's not mayonnaise?
博士さすが！
As expected of the Doctor!
なんでみんなの言葉でわかっちゃうんだよ！
How can you tell just from everyone's words!
博士マジ？しかしケチャップの可能性もある。
Doctor, seriously? But there's also the possibility of ketchup.
しかしね、そうでござるな。
However, that's true.
が、マヨネーズ！
But, mayonnaise!
はい、正解です！
Yes, that's correct!
正解 マヨネーズ
Correct: Mayonnaise
さすが！なんで推理したくなっちゃうんだろう... 頭脳だから。
As expected! I wonder why I want to deduce... because I'm a brain.
やはり頭脳ということでござるな。やってるね。
It means you're indeed a brain. You're on it.
じゃあ次はいろは行ってみようか。
Then, let's have Iroha go next.
はい！じゃあ吾輩が付けてあげるよ。
Yes! Then I'll put it on you.
本当に？届くでござるか？なめてんぬ？
Really? Can you reach? Are you underestimating me?
やぁーっ！
Yaaah!
やりたい放題じゃん！わかったよ、はい、しゃがんでください。
You're just doing whatever you want! I get it, okay, please crouch down.
ああーっ！
Ahhh!
はい、目隠ししました！
Okay, blindfold is on!
なんでわかるの？
How can you tell?
なんか感覚... みんなのいる感覚がすごいな...
Somehow the feeling... the feeling of everyone being there is amazing...
ではいろはに当ててもらうものはこちら！
Then, the thing for Iroha to guess is this!
なんだろう？なに？
What is it? What?
Boxの中身を探れ!!
Identify the contents of the box!!
ちょっと待って
Wait a second
これちょっとヤバい
This is a bit crazy
これヤバい
This is crazy
何だろう、何だろう
What is it, what is it?
え、何これ、ヤバい
Eh, what's this? Crazy
ねえ、間違えて引いちゃうとヤバいかも
Hey, it might be bad if you pull it by mistake
離れて、離れて！離れて！
Stay back, stay back! Stay back!
怖いでござるが、行きます
It's scary, but I'm going in
制限時間は20秒です
The time limit is 20 seconds
いろはのチャレンジ、スタート！
Iroha's challenge, start!
頑張れ！
Good luck!
怖いでござる…
I'm scared...
あ、やめて、やめて！やめて！
Ah, stop it, stop it! Stop it!
いろは、それ引いてもいいんじゃない？
Iroha, shouldn't you just pull that?
そう、それ引いてもいいんだよ
Yeah, it's okay to pull that
いくら…いくらなんでも…
No matter... no matter what...
引かせに行こうとしてるやん！
You're trying to make me pull it!
待って、分かったかも！分かったかも！
Wait, I might know! I might know!
引いていいの？
Is it okay to pull?
クラッカーでござるか？
Is it a party popper?
正解 クラッカー
Correct Answer: Party Popper
正解！
Correct!
危な、恐ろしいもの出してくるね
That was close, you put out scary things
でかいもんね
It's big, after all
あんなに引いていいって言われて引かないの凄いから
It's amazing how you didn't pull it despite being told so much
なんか、後処理のことを考えちゃった
I was just thinking about the cleanup
凄いでたんだけど！見えないって！
So much came out! I can't see!
やりたくなっちゃった
I just really wanted to do it
とんでもなくびっくりした
That incredibly surprised me
クロヱ行ってみようか最後に
Chloe, why don't you go last?
ここまで当たってるからね
We've been right every time so far
怖いよ、なんかいんの？
I'm scared, is there something in there?
私がつけてあげるから
I'll put it on for you
もういいってば！ご機嫌でござるよ！
I said enough already! I'm in a good mood!
誰？何、どこ？
Who is it? What, where?
何にビビってんだよ。大丈夫だって
What are you so scared of? It's fine
クロヱに触ってもらうのはこちら！
What Chloe will be touching is this!
え、何？ヤバい！
Eh, what? This is bad!
怖くて離れちゃった、離れちゃった
I got scared and moved away, I moved away
大丈夫、慣れてる、大丈夫
It's okay, you're used to it, it's fine
早く触れよ！
Touch it already!
まだ動いてないから。大丈夫、大丈夫
It's not moving yet. It's okay, it's okay
制限時間は20秒です
The time limit is 20 seconds
クロヱのチャレンジ、スタート！
Chloe's challenge, start!
待って、動いてる？
Wait, is it moving?
え、何これ、ヤバい！
Eh, what is this? Crazy!
どんな感じ？
How does it feel?
ヌボヌボしてる、中が…
It's slimy... inside...
どんな、え、どんな触感？
What, eh, what texture is it?
生物じゃない？
Isn't it a living thing?
はい、ではクロヱさん、答えをどうぞ
Okay, now Chloe-san, please give your answer
手の匂い嗅ぐな！
Don't smell your hand!
お魚？
A fish?
正解 鯵（アジ）
Correct Answer: Horse Mackerel
正解！
Correct!
アジです
It's a horse mackerel
やったー！
Yay!
絶対生臭くなってるでしょ、手
My hand definitely smells fishy now
ガチで臭いよ
It really stinks
外そう、外そう
Let's take it off, let's take it off
何これ、大きい！
What is this? It's huge!
クロヱには1時間、生臭いままでいてもらいます
We'll have Chloe stay smelling like fish for an hour
本当に臭い！
It really stinks!
静まれ、静まれ
Settle down, settle down
ということで、洞察力はみんな正解ということで
So, everyone was correct with their insight
やったー！
Yay!
任せろって！
Just leave it to me!
次のミッションがあるみたいで
It seems there's another mission
潜入捜査
Undercover Investigation
続いては、潜入捜査！
Next up is Undercover Investigation!
潜入捜査！
Undercover Investigation!
任せんでござる！
Leave it to me!
じゃあチャレンジする企画発表します。
Then, I'll announce the challenge project.
発表します！
Announce it!
すり抜けろ！ holoX Secret Silhouette!
Slip through! holoX Secret Silhouette!
イエーイ！
Yay!
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
え、どういうことなんだろうね。
Uh, I wonder what it means.
何やるの？
What are we doing?
こちらの企画は、すごい広い場所を
For this project, it seems like a very large
用意しているらしいので、まずはそこに移動するらしいですね。
place has been prepared, so we'll move there first.
えっ！？マジで！？
Eh!? Seriously!?
じゃあ移動していきましょう。ジャンプしたら移動できる。
Then let's move. We can move if we jump.
オッケー。
Okay.
行くぞ、せーの！
Let's go, one, two...!
イエーイ！
Yay!
うわぁ！
Whoa!
バラバラすぎんだろ！
We're too scattered!
ジャンプ下手すぎんだろ！
You guys are too bad at jumping!
ということでこの企画はですね、あるシルエットを
So, for this project, objects shaped like
かたどった物体が迫ってくるので、そのシルエットに
certain silhouettes will approach, and you're
合わせてくぐり抜けをしてほしいということだそうです。
asked to pass through them according to that silhouette.
あー、そういうことか。
Ah, I see.
潜入捜査じゃん！
It's like an undercover investigation!
我が輩余裕だって！
I can do this easily!
余裕ですか？
Easily?
余裕だよね。
Easily, right?
じゃあ、実際に見本を見せてもらおうかなと
Then, I'd like to see a demonstration.
思うんですけど。まあこういうのに
Well, there's only one person who's
長けてる人、一人しかいないんだよな。
good at this kind of thing.
我が輩かな？
Me?
お前じゃない。
Not you.
ということでいろは、やってみてもらってもいいかな？
So Iroha, could you try it?
え、いろは？
Eh, Iroha?
用心棒だからね。毒味みたいな感じで。
Because you're the bodyguard. Like a food taster.
確かに！殺る気満々！
True! Full of killing intent!
一番最初に。じゃあ侍、頑張ってね。
The very first one. Then, Samurai, good luck.
頑張って！頑張って！
Good luck! Good luck!
もしかしたら死ぬかもしれないけど。
I might die, though.
見捨てないで！
Don't abandon us!
今までありがとう！
Thank you for everything!
ねえ！ちょっと！
Hey! Wait!
まあでも風真、身を挺して皆のこと守らないといけないからね。
Well, Kazama, you have to protect everyone by putting yourself on the line.
かっこいい！
So cool!
じゃあ見本。っていうのがやってくるのかな？
So, a demo. Is it coming?
やってくるらしいので。
It seems it's coming.
やってくるってどう来るんだろう？
How will it come?
スタートって言えば来るのかな？
Will it come if I say "Start"?
じゃあ行きましょう。
Then let's go.
風真いろはの挑戦です、スタート！
Kazama Iroha's challenge, start!
おおー！来た来た！
Oh! It's here!
えっ、何何？
Eh, what what?
あ、来た！
Ah, it's here!
待って、あそこにあれが。
Wait, that thing over there.
簡単そう。全然大丈夫だね。
Looks easy. I'll be fine.
超簡単じゃない？
Isn't it super easy?
待って待って。え、爆笑じゃん。
Wait, wait. Eh, this is hilarious.
わ、来てる来てる！
Whoa, it's coming, it's coming!
動いてはならぬ。動いてはならぬ。
Must not move. Must not move.
おおー！
Ohhh!
え、なんか簡単じゃない？
Eh, isn't it kind of easy?
爆笑じゃねえか。余裕じゃねえか。
It's hilarious. It's a piece of cake.
やった！
I did it!
これ別に我が輩でもできたじゃん。
I could've done this too.
え、でもなんか角が邪魔そうじゃない？
Eh, but don't the horns look like they'd get in the way?
うるさい、うるさい！退け退け！
Shut up, shut up! Get out of the way!
合格でいいんだけど、じゃあこれは、
That was a pass, so next,
続いてはこより、ルイ、クロヱ、いろは、ラプの順で行こうか。
let's go in the order of Koyori, Lui, Chloe, Iroha, La+.
我が輩がトリってことだな。
So I'm the closer.
見本いっぱい見といてよ。
Watch the demos carefully.
任して任して。
Leave it to us.
さっき堂々としてたからね。じゃあ、こよりが行きます！
You were so confident earlier. Then, Koyori's going!
頑張れ、頑張れ！
Good luck, good luck!
えー、どんなのが来るんだろう。
Eh, I wonder what's coming.
でもさっきの見たらさ、簡単そうだよね。
But looking at the one before, it seems easy.
簡単そうだったね。
It did look easy.
こよりはサバンナを生き抜いてきたこよりですからね。
Koyori is a Koyori who has survived the savannah.
確かに。フラミンゴめっちゃサバンナっぽいね。
True. Flamingos are very savannah-like.
めっちゃフラフラじゃない？
Aren't you swaying a lot?
砂漠だもんな。
It's a desert, after all.
こんなに乾いてないよサバンナ。やめろ！
The savannah isn't this dry. Stop it!
ホーク（フォーク）で遊ぶな！
Don't play with the hawk/fork!
来い！スタートかな？
Come! Start?
おおー！来た来た！
Oh! It's here!
えっ、待って！
Eh, wait!
すごい、逆さま。
Amazing, it's upside down.
待って、待って、待って！え、急におかしいだろ！
Wait, wait, wait! Eh, this is suddenly weird!
行け行け、行ける行ける！
Go, go, you can do it!
こよ、頑張れ！
Koyo, hang in there!
うわぁぁぁ！
Uwaaaah!
こよりちゃん飛んでった！
Koyori-chan flew away!
死んじゃった。
She died.
いい奴だったな。
She was a good person.
今までありがとう！
Thank you for everything!
本当にお疲れ様でした。
Good job out there.
こよりちゃーん！
Koyori-chaaan!
やられたな。尸を越えていけ。
She got taken out. Go over her corpse.
こより任せろ。この私がやってやるよ。
Koyori, leave it to me. I'll do it.
おおー！ルイ姉！
Oh! Lui-nee!
お任せください。一番の長身でちょっと心配なんですけど。
Leave it to me. I'm the tallest so I'm a bit worried.
一番背が高いからできなさそう。
Since you're the tallest, it might be impossible.
危なそうだなぁ。
Seems dangerous.
じゃあ私のはどんなシルエットなんだろう。
Then, I wonder what my silhouette will be.
さっきのから考えると、あれなのか？
Considering the previous one, is it that?
おお！やっぱり！
Oh! Just as I thought!
ジャンプしないといけないじゃん！
You have to jump!
頑張れ、ルイ姉！
Good luck, Lui-nee!
奇跡的に行けるかも。
You might miracle it.
行けー！
Go-!
ルイ姉ー！可哀想ー！
Lui-nee! How pitiful!
おい！ふざけすぎだろ！絶対やってるぞ！
Hey! This is too much! They're definitely doing it on purpose!
ひどかったな今。
That was terrible.
こんなのってないだろ！命がもったいない！
This is ridiculous! What a waste of life!
おかしいんだよ、さっきのいろはと全然違うだろ！
It's weird, it's totally different from Iroha's earlier!
やめましょうよ。次のクロヱにアドバイスをすると、
Let's stop. Advice for Chloe next:
ちょっと早めに飛んどくといいかも。
it might be better to jump a little early.
オッケー、ちょっと早めに。
Okay, a little early.
ジャンプさえすれば行ける可能性がある。
If you just jump, there's a chance.
任せて。
Leave it to me.
これで切り抜けるから
I'll get through with this.
でもここまで来ると、なんか予想できてくるものがあるんだけど
But at this point, I feel like I can start to predict what's coming.
風真、ちょっと嫌な予感しかしない、ちゃんと…
Kazama, I've got a bad feeling about this, just...
それでは、沙花叉の挑戦です！どうぞ！
Now, it's Sakamata's challenge! Go ahead!
予想してる！
I'm predicting it!
え！？無理無理無理無理！
What!? Impossible, impossible, impossible!
行け行け行け行け！
Go go go go!
行ける！行ける！
You can do it! You can do it!
おかしいだろ！
That's just wrong!
飛んでいっちゃった…
She flew away...
絶対おかしい。
That's definitely weird.
いい奴だった…あぁ、お空の彼方に帰ったか。
She was a good person... Ah, she went to the far side of the sky.
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
誰か助けて！
Someone help me!
さぁ、次は誰かな？
Now, who's next?
いい感じだね。
That looks good.
じゃあ次は…いろは、もう一回やってもらってもいい？
Then next... Iroha, could you do it one more time?
あれだけじゃね、終わんないよ。
It won't end with just that.
そうだよ！あれだけじゃ終わらないよ。
That's right! It doesn't end there.
あんな簡単なやつでイキってんじゃねえぞ。
Don't act all high and mighty just because of that easy one.
そんなこと言う。
Don't say that.
何が来るかな。いろはの挑戦はこちら！
I wonder what's coming. Iroha's challenge is this!
はっ！
Ha!
あ、いけそういけそう！
Oh, looks doable!
いけるぞいけるぞ。
You can do it, you can do it.
腕立てでいける？
Can you do it with a push-up?
ちょっと早めに！ちょっと早めに！
A bit earlier! A bit earlier!
いろはちゃーん！
Iroha-chaaan!
だめだったか…
It was no good...
幼児体型なのに。
Even with that child-like build.
いいね、いいね。助けるから。
Nice, nice. We'll help you.
いや、このままじゃ終われないので。じゃあ総帥、最後お願いします！
Well, we can't end it like this. So leader, please take the last turn!
任せとけ！もう。
Leave it to me! Jeez.
取れそう？
Think you can get it?
何言ってんだ！この辺がね、この辺が…
What are you talking about! This part, you see, this part...
やりづらくない？
Doesn't it make it hard?
うるせぇ！前座は黙ってろ！
Shut up! Openers should stay quiet!
自分でも分かってる？この幅。
Do you even realize yourself? This width.
うるせぇ！しかして！
Shut up! However!
吾輩が、もうみんなの悔しい気持ちとか、もう辛い気持ち全部受け止めるから！
I will take all your frustrating feelings and painful feelings upon myself!
長い、長い。ラプラスに挑戦してもらうのは、こちら！
Too long, too long. The challenge for La+ is this!
え！？
What!?
ふざけんな！
Are you kidding me!?
ちょっとしゃがめば。ちょっとしゃがめば。
If you just crouch a bit. If you just crouch a bit.
超簡単、超簡単。
Super easy, super easy.
おかしいだろ！なんでだよ！
That's wrong! Why!?
今の絶対いけたでしょ！
You definitely could have done that just now!
ひどい！やめてください！
Cruel! Please stop!
やめてください。うちの子に…
Please stop. Not to our kid...
大丈夫？大丈夫？ラプラス。
Are you okay? Are you okay, La+?
いじめられたよ…
I was bullied...
いじめられたね。こいつらもできてなかったのに。
You were bullied. Even though these guys couldn't do it either.
そうだ、そうだ！吾輩だけ責められるのはおかしいじゃねえか、馬鹿が！
That's right! Isn't it weird that only I'm getting blamed, you idiots!
いや、これはでも、用意した人がちょっとずるくない？
Well, but isn't the person who prepared this being a bit unfair?
そうだよ、そう。絶対無理だ。
Yeah, exactly. It's impossible.
悪いことしてなくね？
We didn't do anything wrong, right?
なんとかしてクリアしようよ。じゃあ次は、ラプラスと私でやってみるみたいな感じなので。
Let's find a way to clear it. So next, it feels like La+ and I should give it a try.
二人でやってみましょう。
Let's try as a pair.
吾輩たち、伊達に長く一緒にいないから。
We haven't been together all this time for nothing.
やめて、やめて。この中で一番難しそうな二人なんだけど。
Stop, stop. You two look like the hardest combination.
確かに、一番難易度高そうだ。それでは二人が挑戦するのは、こちら！
True, the difficulty seems highest. Well then, the challenge for these two is this!
なんだ？
What is it?
ええ！？
Whaaa!?
何これ！？いけるいける！
What's this!? You can do it!
手、手！無理だよ！
The hands, the hands! No way!
頑張れ！早めに！
Go for it! Do it early!
おかしいだろ！なんでホラミ行けないんだよ！
That's wrong! Why couldn't we go!?
なに怖いここ！もうやめます！世界征服やめます！
This place is scary! I'm quitting! I'm quitting world domination!
酷すぎる。うちの偉い人が飛んでっちゃった。
This is too much. Our high leader flew away.
可哀想だよ。もうこれ、俺ら悪くないよね？
Poor thing. This isn't our fault, right?
ホロックス悪くないよね？
holoX isn't to blame, right?
じゃあなんか最後に、ホロックスの力見せとく？全員でってこと？
Then, as a finale, should we show off holoX's power? You mean all together?
まあ余裕ですよ。
Well, it'll be easy.
いや無理だよ。諦めてんの？
No, it's impossible. Are you giving up?
いけるいける、抜けれるよ。
We can do it, we can get through.
よし、我々ならできるはずだよ。
Alright, we should be able to do it.
ちょっと予行練習しよう。何が来てもいいように。吾輩、こんなんでもいける。
Let's do a little rehearsal. So we're ready for whatever comes. I can even do this.
私はじゃあ、これかな。
Then I'll do... this maybe.
これにこう被せる。じゃあ、五人にやってもらうのは、こちら！
I'll cover it like this. Now, for the five of you, here's your challenge!
えっ！？
What!?
ダメだ！吾輩ここだ！入りきらない！
No good! I'm over here! I won't fit!
待って、風真ないかも、これ。
Wait, Kazama might not be there.
Oだ、O。ワンチャンある？
It's O, O. Is there a chance?
どう、どう？
How is it, how is it?
行け！
Go!
バイバイ。みんなバイバイ。
Bye-bye. Bye-bye everyone.
絶対おかしいよね。ホラミ、また遊び出したの？
This is definitely wrong. Did Holomi start playing around again?
何を考えておるでござるか！
What on earth were you thinking!?
やったー！
Hooray!
吾輩だけクリア！
I'm the only one who cleared it!
えー、じゃあ、なんか、そうだね、ラプラス置いて、アジトに戻ろうか。
Well then, how about we leave Laplus behind and head back to the hideout?
あ、そうだね。
Ah, that sounds like a good idea.
なんで！？待って！
Wait, why?!
じゃあね！じゃあね！バイバイ！
See ya! See ya! Bye-bye!
待ってー！行かないで！
Wait! Don't go!
バイバーイ！お疲れ！お疲れ！
Bye-bye! Good work! Good work!
やだー！行かないでー！
Nooo! Don't go!
あー、ただいまー。疲れたー。
Ah, we're back. So tired.
もう夢落ちだったってこと？
So it was all just a dream?
皆、先に帰っちゃうから、走ってきたんだぞ、吾輩！
You all left without me, so I had to run back!
えらい、えらい、えらい。頑張った、頑張った。おめでとう。頑張った。
Good girl, good girl. You did your best. Congrats, you worked hard.
で、どうだった？この企画。洞察力と潜入捜査。
So, how was this project? Insight and undercover investigation.
何が潜入なんだよ！誰も潜入してないでござる！
What do you mean undercover?! Nobody was undercover!
潜入捜査、かなりきつかったよね。
The undercover investigation was pretty tough, wasn't it?
そうだね、きつかったよ。なんか、いじめられてないですか？これ。
Yeah, it was. Wait, aren't we just being bullied here?
確かに、おかしいでござる。何が潜入捜査だ！
True, it is weird. undercover investigation, my foot!
もう、毎回これやるなよ、もう。何？これ、うるさいだけだ！
Geez, don't do this every time. What is this? It's just noisy!
皆さん、いかがでしたか？
How was it, everyone?
さて次が最後になります。
Now, it's time for the final part.
秘密結社に一番必要な能力、わかりますよね？
You know the most essential skill for a secret society, right?
金！力！権力！
Money! Power! Authority!
力こそパワー！
Might is power!
何？筋肉？分かった。
What? Muscles? I get it.
筋肉じゃないだろ。多分、あの、5人で力を合わせて頑張るっていうことで、団結力。
It's not muscles. It's probably about the five of us working together, unity.
団結力
Unity
おー！言っちゃったよ、言っちゃった。
Oh! You said it, you said it.
そうだね。てか、さっき団結力ないこと分かったし。もう、やってったって大丈夫でござる。メモにデカデカと書いちゃった。
Right. I mean, we already saw we have no unity. We'll be fine. I already wrote it down in huge letters in my notes.
団結力か。でも、長いこと一緒にいるから普通にあるんじゃね？
Unity, huh? But we've been together for a long time, so we should have some, right?
余裕じゃない？
Should be a breeze, right?
てか、何やらされるの？
Wait, what are they going to make us do?
というわけで最後にチャレンジしてもらうのは...
And so, the final challenge for you is...
なんと...
It's...
溜めるなよ！溜めるな！
Don't build up the suspense! Don't build it up!
大縄跳びです。
Long rope jumping.
大縄！？何？運動会？おふざけんな、体育館じゃねえんだよ、ここは！
Long rope?! What? Is this a sports day? Stop messing around, this isn't a gym!
あの、帰ります。失礼します。苦手でしょう、これ、無理だよ。
Um, I'm going home. Excuse me. We're bad at this, it's impossible.
やだ！もうやだ、本当。帰るなら誘えよ！
No! I'm done, seriously. If you're going home, take me with you!
ではチャレンジお願いします。やだやだやだ！
Now, please start the challenge. No, no, no!
じゃあ、10回飛んでください。厳しいですか？
Well then, please jump 10 times. Is that too hard?
でも、あの、いろはに一人で10回飛ばせれば...。団結力のほうに行っちゃうんだよ、団結力のほう。
But, if we just let Iroha jump 10 times by herself... wait, that's not unity at all.
でも、これは団結力でござるから、皆で飛ばないといかんでござる。
But since this is about unity, we all have to jump together.
えー、めんどくさーい。
Ugh, what a pain.
あ、なんかここに縄が！
Ah, look, there's a rope here!
縄、縄の罠が。ホロゾーからの縄の罠が。
A rope, a rope trap. A rope trap from Holo-zo.
大丈夫かな。えー、吾輩回すのめんどくさい。
I wonder if we'll be okay. Ugh, I don't want to be the one swinging it.
あ、じゃあ、ここはお姉さん組で。そうだね。
Ah, then how about the older sister group takes that role? Good idea.
坂又飛ぶでござるよ。えー、飛ばなきゃいけないの？
Sakamata, you're jumping. Ugh, I have to jump?
え、坂又苦手なの？え、いや、得意でござる。
Wait, Sakamata, are you bad at this? Oh, no, I'm great at it.
嘘つき。お姉さん、生きるの辞めろよ、もう。大丈夫だって。
Liar. Sis, just give up on life already. It'll be fine.
すぐ生きる辞めるやん。え、ちょっと、最後でいい？怖いから。いいよ。
You're always giving up on life. Can I go last? I'm scared. Sure.
あ、怖くない、怖くないけど最後。風間から入って、ラプ、殿、の順？
I'm not scared, I'm not, but I'll go last. So, Kazama enters first, then Lap, then Master?
いいよ。そう、一番最初が一番きついと思うから。この辺は任せるでござる、風間に。
Alright. Yeah, I think going first is the toughest part. I'll leave this to Kazama.
マジで怖くなってきた。いろはに任せようかな。全部いろはでいいじゃん、もう。
I'm getting really scared. Maybe I'll leave it all to Iroha. Let's just have Iroha do everything.
じゃあ、いろは、ラプラス、クロヱの順ね。分かった。
Then the order will be Iroha, Laplus, Chloe. Got it.
あれだよ、クロヱ、頑張って入らないと。あ、そうだ。クロヱが入らないと1回にならないから。そうだね、早く入ってこいよ。
Listen, Chloe, you have to work hard to jump in. Ah, that's right. It doesn't count as one jump until Chloe is in. Right, so jump in quickly.
入ってから1回だよ。嘘、そうなの？そう。え、皆で飛ぶんだもんね、これ。オッケー、坂又頑張るよ。
It's one jump after you're in. What, really? Yeah. Well, we're all jumping together, after all. Okay, Sakamata will do her best.
とりあえず、大縄跳びスタート！
Anyway, long rope jumping, start!
じゃあ、行きますよ。はい。
Alright, here we go. Yes.
ほい！はい！早い早い早い！
Hup! Yes! Quick, quick, quick!
早く来い！あ、クロヱ、クロヱ、縄、縄！
Hurry up and come in! Ah, Chloe, Chloe, the rope, the rope!
やるじゃないですか。
Not bad, are you?
我が輩たち、運動神経よすぎ。よかった、よかった。
Our athletic nerves are too good. Good, good.
じゃあ、2人で我が輩回してあげるよ。
Then, two of you turn the rope for me.
えっ、でも私、いつも飛んでるからな。
Wait, but I'm always jumping.
頼む、回して、我が輩も回したいよ。
Please, let me turn it, I want to turn it too.
じゃあ、もう一回やる？
Then, want to do it again?
回して、回して。
Turn it, turn it.
で、いろはもやってみたかった？
And Iroha, did you want to try too?
やってみたかった！OK!
I wanted to try! OK!
風真も飛ぶね！
Kazama will jump too!
次はこれでまた10回できたら凄くないか？
Won't it be amazing if we can do 10 times again like this?
いろは、疲れてる？
Iroha, are you tired?
あ、全然大丈夫でござるよ。
Ah, I'm perfectly fine.
お前、疲れとか知らんのか。
You, don't you know what fatigue is?
じゃあ、ちょっとお言葉に甘えて、いろは、ルイ、こよりでいこうか。
Then, I'll take you up on that, let's go with Iroha, Lui, and Koyori.
我が輩と沙花叉で回すから。
Me and Sakamata will turn the rope.
思い出作りや、思い出作り。
Making memories, making memories.
じゃ、行くぞ。せーの！
Then, here we go. One, two!
やるじゃないですか。
Not bad, are you?
すごいね。やるじゃないか。2回目、2回目。2回目ね。
Amazing. Not bad. The second time, the second time. Second time, right.
というわけで、秘密結社holoXの配信を終えさせていただきます。
And so, we'll be ending the secret society HoloX stream.
引き続き、精進してください。
Please continue to devote yourselves.
じゃあ、最後にカッコいいところ見せてもらいましょう。
Then, let's see something cool at the end.
違うだろー！
That's not it!
じゃあ、ちょっと最後にカッコいいところ見せるか。
Then, let's show something cool at the end.
お前ら、5人でライブするぞ！
Everyone, let's do a live as five!
いくぞー！
Here we go!
さあ 1 2 3 で 踊りだせ 精神攪乱 I 8
Come on, dance at 1 2 3, mental disturbance I 8
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイが バンド仲間にヤッホー
Subculture boy with a Telecaster on his back says 'Yahoo' to his bandmates
アルバイトはねるモード 対バンにはATフィールド
Mode after part-time job, AT field against other bands
人見知り 宣戦布告 いざ ぎんぎん ギガボイ
Shyness, declaration of war, now gin-gin giga-boy
言うて お坊ちゃん お嬢ちゃん お金も 才能も 生まじか あるだけ 厄介でやんす
As I said, young masters and misses, having only money and talent is just a bother
Boys be ambitious Like this old man
長い前髪 君 誰の信者
Long bangs, whose believer are you?
信者
Believer
勘違いすんな 教祖はお前だ
Don't get it wrong, you're the leader
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール エレクトリックギターは Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
Roki-roki rockin' rockin' roll, electric guitar is Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
かき鳴らしては 曝け出せ 見せろよ
Strumming along, expose it, show it
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki rockin' rockin' roll
さあ 自撮り棒 1曲書いてる？
Come on, selfie stick, are you writing a song?
フォロワー増えてる？
Are your followers increasing?
知名度あるけど人気はそんなにないから 色々大変ですね
Famous but not that popular, so it's tough in many ways
勝手に有名 匿名アイコン 実は見せない 実写のアカウント
Famous without permission, anonymous icon, actually not showing the real account
必死こいて自意識マザーファッカー
Desperately self-conscious motherfucker
ぶっちゃけ どんだけ 賢く あざとく やったって
10年後にメイクは落ちてんだよ
To be honest, no matter how smart or cunning you are,
your makeup will be gone in 10 years.
Boy on the mission (ハイハイ)
Boy on the mission (Yes, yes)
Like a sword of the man (えっ?)
Like a sword of the man (Eh?)
生き抜くためだ 決めろセルフィー
It's for survival, so take a selfie.
セルフィー
Selfie
死ぬんじゃねーぞ お互いにな
Don't you go dying on me now, either of us.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
薄っぺらいラブソングでもいい
Even a shallow love song will do.
さあ君の目の前のやつを ぶち抜いてみせろよ
Now, go and blow away that person in front of you.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
お茶を濁してちゃ満足できない
I can't be satisfied with being vague.
スタジオに運ばれて数十分
It's been dozens of minutes since I was brought to the studio.
ぶっちゃけ 不安でプレッシャーでいっぱい
To be honest, I'm full of anxiety and pressure.
実は昨日から風邪で声が出ません
Actually, I've had a cold since yesterday and lost my voice.
はぁ？
Huh?
寝言は寝て言え
Save your sleep-talking for when you're asleep.
Baby Baby Baby Baby Baby Baby
死ぬんじゃねーぞ お互いにな
Don't you go dying on me now, either of us.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
掻き鳴らすエレクトリックギターは
The electric guitar that's strummed is...
さあ君の全てを さらけ出してみせろよ
Now, go and show me everything about yourself.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
ロキロキの
Roki Roki's
ロックンロール
Rock n' Roll
死ぬんじゃねーぞ
Don't you go dying.
死にたがれぬのはお互い様
Not being able to die is mutual.
パッと首吊る前にパンプを繋いで
Before you suddenly hang yourself, plug in the pump.
ストラト背負ってクラファン弾いて
Put on your Strat and play some crowdfunding.
テレキャス持った学生しばいて
Beat up some students with Telecasters.
さあトリップしよう
Now, let's trip.
愛すべき世界へ
To the world we should love.
脱法ロック
作詞・作曲：Neru
Dappou Rock
Lyrics & Composition: Neru
なんて時代に生まれたもんだ
What a time to be born in.
ドラえもんはいないし ポッケはないし
There's no Doraemon, and no pocket.
バカは治りゃしないし
Fools can't be cured.
もうどうにでもなれ
Whatever, anything goes.
天国が呼んでいる
Heaven is calling.
千鳥足でスワップパーティ
A swap party with staggering steps.
どうせ萎びている
We're withered anyway.
早く音量を上げてくれ
Hurry up and turn the volume up.
現実逃避だ
It's an escape from reality.
負けないなんて吠えろ
Howl that you won't lose.
理想なんて捨てろ
Throw away your ideals.
それが脱法ロックの礼法なんですわ
That's the etiquette of Dappou Rock.
変に沈め
Sink in a strange way.
社会的強者の面を
At the faces of the social elite.
先制パンチ決めろ
Deliver a preemptive punch.
それが脱法ロックの礼法なんですわ
That's the etiquette of Dappou Rock.
年中生きていこう
Let's live all year round.
吸って吐いて
Inhale, exhale,
それが脱法ロックの
that's the Dappou Rock
作法なんですわ
etiquette.
天才なんて知らない
I don't know about geniuses,
知らない
I don't know.
ボリュームを一つも
Don't turn down
下げない 下げない
the volume, not one bit.
のべつ幕なし 決めろ 決めろ
Without a moment's rest, strike a pose, strike a pose.
それが脱法ロックの
That's the Dappou Rock
作法なんですわ
etiquette.
年中イキっていこう
Let's keep showing off all year round!
Wow wow wow wow...
（歓声と拍手）
(Cheering and applause)
ノキトと脱法ロック聴いていただきました！
You've just listened to 'Nokito' and 'Dappou Rock'!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
盛り上がってもらえましたかー！？
Did you guys get hyped up!?
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much!
めちゃくちゃ疲れたね！
That was exhausting!
体力を酷使してたね。
That really took a lot out of us.
めちゃくちゃ良かった。
It was amazing.
ラプラスどうだった？
La+, how was it?
この5人でライブしたのが初めてだったから、楽しかった！
It was our first time performing live as a group of five, so it was fun!
ねー！
Yeah!
初集合、良かったー！
Our first gathering was great!
やっぱライブすると違うよね。
Performing live really is different.
声の感じがめちゃ合ってたね。
Our voices blended together so well.
歌、めちゃめちゃ良かった。
The singing was really good.
お前ら、歌うめーじゃん！
You guys are actually pretty good at singing!
どうも、どうも！
Thank you, thank you!
お、ここでお知らせがあるみたいですね。
Oh, it looks like there's an announcement.
じゃあここでお知らせだ！
Alright, time for an announcement!
なんと、我らホロライブ3Dアクリルスタンドに秘密結社holoXが追加されるぞ！
Guess what? Secret Society holoX is being added to the Hololive 3D Acrylic Stands!
ホロライブ 3Dアクリルスタンド
秘密結社holoX > 6月30日追加販売開始
Hololive 3D Acrylic Stand
Secret Society holoX > Additional sales start June 30
やったー！
Hooray!
これ、再現しようよ。
Let's recreate the pose.
せーの！はい！
One, two... there!
いけてるかな？いい感じだね。
How do we look? Pretty good, right?
いいじゃん、いいじゃん！
Nice, nice!
これで見ても可愛いね。まとまりがあるわ。
They look so cute even like this. Very cohesive.
我らのアーティスト写真的なやつになるわけだね。
It's like our official artist photo.
決まりました、これが宣材写真です！
It's decided, this is our promotional photo!
みんな覚えてください！
Everyone, please remember this!
一人一人のやつ見たいな。
I want to see each one individually.
じゃあ見せてあげる。商品の画像はこちら！
I'll show you. Here are the product images!
可愛いー！いいじゃん！
So cute! They're great!
全身ちゃんと映ってるね。
You can see the whole body.
しかもサイズちょっと大きいよね？
And the size is a bit big, isn't it?
全員まとめて買ってほしいね。
I hope people buy the whole set.
並べてほしいなー！
I want them all lined up!
風呂場とかに並べておきたい。
I want to line them up in the bathroom or something.
これ、先輩方のやつと同じ大きさだから、みんなと並べてください。
Since these are the same size as our seniors', please line us up with them.
組み合わせとかもできるしね。
You can make different combinations.
こちらはホロライブプロダクション公式ショップにて、このあと21時から販売開始だ！
These go on sale at the Hololive Production Official Shop starting at 9 PM today!
さらに、これだけじゃないぞ！
And that's not all!
なんと！
What!?
加速するぞ！秘密結社holoX 3Dお披露目記念グッズが販売開始だ！
Picking up the pace! Secret Society holoX 3D Celebration Goods are now on sale!
秘密結社holoX 3Dお披露目記念
6月30日販売開始
Secret Society holoX 3D Celebration
Sales start June 30
やったー！ポーズが違う！
Hooray! The poses are different!
カッコイイ！みんな表情がすごい。
Cool! Everyone's expressions are great.
そして、まずはこちら！
And first up, this!
我ら、秘密結社holoXアクリルジオラマスタンド！
Our Secret Society holoX Acrylic Diorama Stand!
ジオラマなんだ！
It's a diorama!
今回お披露目したアジトに我らが全員集合したジオラマスタンドになってるぞ！
It's a diorama stand featuring all of us gathered in the hideout we revealed today!
めちゃくちゃいい！集合感あるね。
That's awesome! It really feels like we're all together.
一緒に飾ってほしいね。
I'd love for people to display it.
このポーズもみんなで一生懸命考えたんだよね。
We all worked hard thinking up these poses, right?
みんな写真撮られるって言ってウキウキだったね。
Everyone was so excited about getting their picture taken.
前で座る？とか後ろ？とか言って。
We were like, "Should I sit in front?" or "Should I be in back?"
考えただけあってめちゃくちゃ揃っててカッコイイ！
It looks so cool and coordinated, probably because we thought about it so much!
我ら！って感じだね。こちらもぜひ手に入れてくれ！
It really captures our vibe. Please be sure to get one!
そして、holoX シークレットコンテナボックス！
And, the holoX Secret Container Box!
あ、さっきのやつだ！
Oh, the one from earlier!
我らがアジトで使用しているボックスで、貴様らholoXerの分も量産してやったぞ！
It's the box we use in our hideout, and we've mass-produced them for all you holoXers too!
ありがたき幸せ！お菓子入れるじゃん。
We're so grateful! I'm gonna put snacks in it.
ふざけんな！お菓子とか言うなよ！
Don't be silly! Don't say things like snacks!
お揃いなんだからね。お菓子とか言うなよ、秘密だぞ。
We're matching, you know. Don't mention snacks, it's a secret.
まあとにかくみんな手に入れてくれよな！
Anyway, I hope everyone gets their hands on one!
ということで、次が最後の曲だ！
And with that, our next song will be the last one!
行け！ あー！
Go! Aaaah!
昨日も今日も晴天で　入道雲を見ていた
Yesterday and today were clear, I was watching the cumulonimbus clouds.
怠いくらいの快晴だ　目を細めて
A clear day, so bright it's tiring; narrowing my eyes.
それはどうも簡単に　思い出せやしないようで
It seems I can't recall it that easily.
年を取った現状に　浸ってたんだよ
I was soaking in the reality of getting older.
大人ぶった作戦で　不思議な合図送って
With a plan like we're grown-ups, sending mysterious signals.
「行こうか、今日も戦争だ」　立ち向かって手を取った
"Shall we go? Today's a battle too." We faced it and took each other's hands.
理不尽なんて当然で　独りを強いられたって
Absurdity is only natural, even if forced into loneliness.
迷った僕は憂鬱に　なりそうになってさ
Lost and confused, I was about to fall into melancholy.
背高草（せたかそう）を分けて　滲む太陽睨んで
Pushing through the tall grass, glaring at the blurring sun.
君がさ、こう言ったんだ
And then you said this.
「孤独だったらおいでよ」
"If you're lonely, come on over."
騒がしい坂を越して　生まれた感情さえも
Even the emotions born from crossing that noisy slope...
頭に浮かんで沈んだ　「わがまますぎるかなぁ」
...floated into my head and sank: "Is this too selfish?"
秘密基地に集まって　「楽しいね」って単純な
Gathering at the secret base, "This is fun," such simple...
あの頃を思い出して　話をしよう
...memories of those days; let's talk about them.
飛行機雲飛んでって　「眩しいね」って泣いていた
The vapor trail flew away, "It's so bright," we were crying.
君はどんな顔だっけ　何故だろう、思い出せないな
What kind of face did you have? Why is it that I can't remember?
痛いくらい現実は　足早に駆け抜けた
Reality dashed past so fast it almost hurt.
選んだ今日は平凡で　崩れそうになる日々を
The today I chose is ordinary, these days that feel like they're crumbling.
昨日も今日は延長戦　大人だって臆病だ
Yesterday and today are extra innings, even adults are cowards.
今になってはなんとなく　気付けたみたいだよ
I think I've finally realized that now.
廻る世界のイデア　枯れる太陽　炎天下
The idea of the revolving world, the withering sun, under the blazing heat.
陽炎が揺らいだ　「忘れないでさ、進もう」
The heat haze shimmered, "Don't forget, let's move forward."
櫨（もど）かしい蝉時雨　明日を夢に見ていた
The frustrating chorus of cicadas, I was dreaming of tomorrow.
戻らない先のある世界へ　僕たちで変えよう
To a world with a future we can't return from, let's change it ourselves.
「思い出して、終わったって」
"Remember, even if it's over."
秘密基地も冒険も
The secret base and the adventures.
あの日に迷い込んだ
That day we wandered into...
話し合うことも
...talking with each other too.
独りぼっちが集まった
The lonely ones gathered together.
子供たちの作戦が
The children's plan...
また今日も廻りだした
...has started revolving again today.
「また、何処かで」
"See you again, somewhere."
「涼しいね」って言い合った　夏空は透明だ
"It's cool, isn't it?" we said to each other, the summer sky is transparent.
泣かないように吸い込んで　「サヨナラ」をしよう
Breathe it in so you don't cry, and let's say "Goodbye."
秘密基地に集まって　笑い合った夏の日に
Gathering at the secret base, on that summer day we laughed together.
「また何処かで」っと思い出して　出逢えるかな、なんて
"See you again somewhere," I remember, wondering if we'll meet again.
何度でも　描こう
Let's draw it, again and again.
holoxerの皆殿！！ いつも我々holoXを応援して下さり本当にありがとうございますでござる♨ これからも5人で元気に頑張っていくのでずっと見守っていてくださいね！！ holoXとholoxerの皆殿を皆、大好きでござるよ〜！ 風真いろは
To all holoxers!! Thank you for always supporting us holoX de-gozaru♨ We will continue to do our best as 5 energetic members, so please keep watching over us!! I love holoX and all the holoxers! - Kazama Iroha
沙花叉もholoXを見守ってくれて愛してくれてありがとう。これからも一緒に歩み合おうね。大好きだよ！ 沙花叉クロヱ
Thank you for watching over and loving Sakamata and holoX. Let's continue to walk together from now on. I love you! - Sakamata Chloe
いつも応援を観てくれてありがとう！これからもこよ達と一緒にいっぱい笑って楽しもう！！ holoxerのみんな、大好きだぞ〜〜っ！ 5人の成長を見守ってください🐾 博衣こより
Thank you for always watching our support! Let's continue to laugh and have fun with Koyo and the others!! I love all the holoxers~~! Please watch over the growth of the five of us🐾 - Hakui Koyori
！！いつもholoXを見守ってくれてありがとう！ 不器用な5人ですが、これからも力を合わせて成長していくから近くでよりそってくれるかな！？ holoxerのみんなが大好き♡ Thank You な 鷹嶺ルイ
!! Thank you for always watching over holoX! We are 5 clumsy people, but we will continue to grow together, so will you stay close by us!? I love all the holoxers♡ Thank You - Takane Lui
わがはいのHoloXが最強だ！ La+ Darknesss
My HoloX is the strongest! - La+ Darknesss
世界征服
World Domination
World Conquest